准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
兴风作浪
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
蟹堡王
这放秘方的保险柜也太耐用了
That secret formula safe is pretty durable
也许根本就不该用炸药的
Maybe dynamite was the wrong choice
员工们  我得暂时远离痞老板一阵子
Crew, I need to get away from Plankton for a while
我需要度个假
I could use a vacation
来场海上游轮之旅
A nice sea cruise
坐游轮啊
A cruise
玩沙壶球
The shuffleboard
[ 沙壶球：双方轮流将壶推向长桌尽头
每局8球，球全推出后，最远者为本轮的胜方 ]
吃自助
The buf
餐
fet
还有晕船
The sea sickness
我们能
We can--
没有们
Not we
只有我
Me
就我去
Alone
住单人舱
Cabin for one
章鱼哥先生  重建蟹堡王
Mr. Squidward, rebuild the restaurant
我能干嘛呢
What should I do?
祝我一路顺风
Wish me bon voy-ah-gee
一路顺风
Bon voyage
再见
Goodbye
告辞
Farewell
旅途愉快
Happy trails
为什么
Why?
为什么你一定要走
Why do you have to go?
我已经想死你了
I miss you already
别丢下我啊
Don't leave me
好耶
Oh, boy
这下就能去帮章鱼哥了
Now I get to help Squidward
看来我的客舱在楼下
Looks like my cabin's downstairs
对  我先前是办伙食的
Yes, I was the purveyor
还得再下多少层啊
How much further down do these decks go?
倾斜
通缉
见过这人吗
237号客舱
Cabin 237
找到了
Here we go
里面比蜗牛壳还小
It's tighter than a snail's shell in here
起码入住费还挺便宜的
But at least I got it cheap
老螃蟹
Krabs?
老痞子
Plankton
你来干什么
What are you doing here?
我还想远离你呢
I'm tryin' to get away from you
这可是我的客舱
This is my cabin
我也还想远离你呢
And I'm trying to get away from you
这可是我的客舱
This is my cabin
尤金蟹
237号房
双人入住
谢尔顿痞
237号房
双人入住
"Double occupancy"?
整场游轮旅行都别让我看到听到你
I better not see you
and I better not hear you for this whole cruise
不然海神王保佑
or so help me, Neptune
到时我就把你的绿屁股丢到海里去
I'm tossin' your green keister overboard
是吗
Oh, yeah?
老子也会甩门
Well, I can slam a hatch too, ya know
果汁吧
欢迎旅客登船
Well, ahoy there, passenger
我是鲁布  船上的活动负责人
I'm Rube, the activities director on this ship
要报名游玩我们狂野湿滑的水滑梯吗
Can I sign you up for our wet and wild waterslide?
太神了  对吧
Amazing, isn't it?
感觉并不
I don't think
神
so
保证你会玩得特开心
You're gonna have fun
再找个伙伴配你一起滑就行
You just need a buddy to go down with
说伙伴伙伴到
And here's your buddy now
老螃蟹
Krabs
老痞子
Plankton
很好
Good
原来你们早认识了啊
You already know each other
起锚了
Anchors aweigh
等下
Wait
说  伙伴
Say "Buddies"
我非谴责你不可
I rebuke you
离我远一点
Get away from me
[ 此为前面海绵所述的沙壶球 ]
好耶  宝贝
Yeah, baby
十分
Ten points
痞老板又赢了
Plankton wins again
自个儿玩就是不会输
You can't lose when you play alone
滚远点  鲸鱼口粮
Buzz off, whale food
这球场已经被我约走了
I'm signed up for this court now
咬藤壶去吧你
Go bite a barnacle
我预约的才对
I'm booked right now
不好意思
Fish sticks
我不小心帮你们预约到了同一段时间
I signed you both up for the same time
希望那样不成问题
I hope that won't be a prob
没问题
No prob
太神了
Amazing
滚开  傻壶螃蟹
Shuffle off, Krabs
没错
That's right
船长说  铲煤
The captain says, "Shoveling coal
是你俩疯子
is what you two maniacs get
在我船上闹事的惩罚
for causing trouble on my ship"
祝你们开心哦
So have fun, y'all
真谢谢你了  谢尔顿
Thanks a lot, Sheldon
我假期都被你糟蹋了
You ruined my vacation
全体成员
All hands on deck
船失控了
We've lost control of the ship
海神王保佑  我们就快撞上冰山了
Neptune help us, we're headed straight for an iceberg
冰 山
就前边那个结球生菜
lettuce, dead ahead
不敢相信我居然会跟你一块儿独处
I can't believe I'm left here alone with just you
我也不信我居然会跟你一块儿独处
Well, I can't believe I'm left here alone with just you too
起码还有免费沙拉
At least we have free salad
烂
Boo
滚越远越好
Good riddance
我恨死你们了
I hate you so
可不可以丢点千岛酱下来
Can ya throw down some Thousand Island dressing?
你们两位好啊
Ahoy there, you two
谁要来做救生艇演练啊
Now who's up for a lifeboat drill?
好吧  下次再说
Okay, maybe next time
水好冷啊  冷到我腿都麻了
The water's so cold I can barely feel my legs
太神了
Ah-mayyy-zing
好  开始划船吧
Okay, let's start paddling
你划错方向了
You're going the wrong way
不对  划这方向
No, this way
不对
No
划这方向
This way
正确的方向
The right way
第二天
这方向才是正确的方向吗
This way is the right way, eh?
划这方向就被困住了
Well, this way we're stranded
你脚踩到我这半边的荒岛来了
Your foot is on my side of the deserted island
还不是你老乱改界线
Well, you keep moving the line
你们两个在这啊
There you two are
我到处都在找你们呢
I've been looking for you all over
我帮你俩都报了名  一起到沙滩骑行
I've got you both signed up for a bike ride on the beach
这是给你量身定制的活动
Here's an activity for you
投得挺准
Nice throw
谢了
Thanks
打气筒给我
Hand me that bicycle pump
你要干嘛
What are you doing?
我要骑着橡胶裤离开这里
I'm gonna ride ol' rubber pants outta here
别丢下我
Not without me
不会吧
Oh, no
我肚子好胀啊
I'm all bloated
最好解开一下腰带
Better undo my belt
别啊
Don't
不要
No
太神了
Ah-may-ziiiing
脚趾头好凉快
That is brisk on the little piggies
有宝藏
Treasure
早安
Good morning
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
你来干什么
What are you doing here?
我向来都会来酷乐湖寻宝
I always come to Goo Lagoon to look for treasure
有一次我找到了个瓶盖
Once I found a bottle cap
酷乐湖
Goo Lagoon?
你之前还说那些声音是幻听
You said all those sounds were hallucinations
还不是你膝盖不中用  不肯逛岛
Well, you wouldn't explore the island
because of your knees
够了
That's it
这下我真得要来趟假期远离你了
Now I really need a vacation from you
我还更得要来趟假期远离你
Not as much as I need one from you
一周后
蟹堡王
蟹堡工
这边最近真是安静得很
Sure has been quiet around here
海之霸
这边最近真是无聊得很
It sure has been boring around here
你好
Yello
老螃蟹
Krabs
老痞子
Plankton
你背后藏了什么  尤金
What'cha got there behind your back, Eugene?
我只是觉得
Well, I just thought
就是  你应该会比较想
ya know, you might wanna
也许
maybe
来试试看  就那个
take a crack at, uh, ya know
偷我秘方
stealing me formuler?
拿来吧你
Gimme that
它干嘛跑这边来了
What is this doing here?
平平安安
Safe and sound
你们两个好啊
Ahoy there, you two
看来咱都报名来这参加转瓶子游戏了
Looks like we're all signed up in here
for a game of Spin The Bottle
太神了
Ah-maaayyy-zing
类星体船长 下一代
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
类星体船长
Captain Quasar
救救我
Save me
把派大机放了  鸡嘴哥
You let Pat-Tron go, Chicken Man
海神王啊  你身后那啥东西
Sweet Neptune, what's that behind you?
我的英雄
My hero
你救了我
You saved me
那当然了  派大机
Of course, Pat-Tron
谁都不许欺负类星体船长的船员
Nobody messes with Captain Quasar's crew
这集真好看
What an episode
打斗真精彩
What a battle
类星体船长再次大获成功
Captain Quasar does it again
这集拥抱的戏我都喜欢
I liked all the hugging
你们说外面不会真的有鸡嘴哥吧
Guys, you don't suppose
there's real Chicken Men out there, do you?
当然没有了  派大星
Of course not, Patrick
都是做电视节目虚构出来的
They're just made up for TV
就像动画片  或者法国
like cartoons, or France
呼唤全体类星体船长粉丝
Calling all Captain Quasar fans
速来类星体船长粉丝俱乐部
Your presence is required
at the only Captain Quasar fan club
三海地区独家限定
in the tri-ocean area
裤头村
快快传送到我们总部
Beam over to our headquarters
超棒漫画店
地址就在漫画店后面
in the back of the comic book shop
下一场会议日期是太空日76359-1
The next meeting is on space-date 76359-1
旧月
就是今天  你们几位太空学员
That's today, ya space cadets
一定要加入粉丝俱乐部
We gotta join that fan club
快看
Look
仅限硬核
类星体粉丝
换油半价
"Half Price Oil Change"
不对  派大星
No, Patrick
上面写的是  仅限硬核类星体粉丝
it says, "Hardcore Quasar Fans Only"
我可硬汉了
I'm hard-boiled
大家快一点
Hurry up, guys
你们好
Greetings
欢迎光临类星体船长官方粉丝俱乐部
Welcome to the Official Captain Quasar Fan Club
我海霸王  很明显就是部长
I, Bubble Bass, am president, obviously
哈维跟凯文是联合秘书
Harvey and Kevin are co-secretaries
我们一直都在寻找新成员
We are always on the lookout for new members
然而  依你们破破烂烂的皮套来看
However, judging by your rather shabby cosplay
估计你们都是旧版类星体剧粉吧
I surmise you are fans of the original Quasar series
这家粉丝俱乐部只粉重启版
This fan club is only for the reboot
类星体船长  下一代
Captain Quasar: The Next Iteration
所以类星体船长做了新版的吗
They made a new Captain Quasar show?
没错
Indeed
而且新版好看不少
And it is the far superior series
因此  这些你们用不上了
Therefore, you won't be needing any of this
会议开头呢
Now, to begin our meeting
先来看一段新版片段吧
let's watch a clip from the new show
派大机  启动阿尔法式机甲
Pat-Tron, activate Mecha Pattern Alpha
上菜了
Dinner is served
所以等下
So, wait
类星体船长现在变机甲片了吗
now Captain Quasar is a giant robot show?
主题应该是探索宇宙才对吧
I thought it was about exploring the universe
可以两者兼得
It can be both
不行
Nope
那样基本设定就乱套了
It confuses the premise
我支持鱿鱼妹
I'm with Squidina
旧版类星体  好看
Original Quasar, yay
类星体
重启版类星体  不好看
Reboot Quasar, nay
新类星体
我喜欢新版
I like the new one
这机器人可帅了
The robot is so handsome
行
Fine
俱乐部就你们办去吧
You guys can have your club
我们要办自己的俱乐部
We're gonna start our own
专门粉旧版
to celebrate the original series
来吧  海绵宝宝
Come on, SpongeBob
天啊
Oh boy
能开新俱乐部真是超级激动  鱿鱼妹
I'm super excited for our new club, Squidina
可是
But, uh
俱乐部会议要上哪开呢
where are we having the meeting?
不是可以在你家开吗
I thought we could do it at your place?
虽然我很乐意
I'd love to
但小蜗已经说好要征用我家了
but Gary said he needed the house to himself today
我知道可以去哪了
I know a place we can go
跟我来
Follow me
这地方有点挤啊  海绵宝宝
This place is a little tight, SpongeBob
没错
True
但是有零食吃
But it comes with snacks
来开会吧
Let's start our meeting
先做类星体船长秘密俱乐部握手式
with the Captain Quasar secret club handshake
类星体学员  发射
Quasar Cadets, blast off
海绵宝宝  你干嘛
SpongeBob, what are you doing?
应该要发射才对的
We're supposed to blast off
我已经尽力在发射了
I'm blasting off as hard as I can
我薯片被个黄色玩意给卡住了
My chips are caught on some yellow thing
再买一袋呗  把你原先那袋顶出来
Buy another bag, it'll knock your chips loose
看来必须得使出
Looks like I'll have to give it the old
新版类星体摇
new Quasar shake
万岁
Huzzah
免费零食
Free snacks
类星体
Quasar
想吐
Queasy
我能想到的地方全都试过了
Well, we tried the only place I could think of
看来也没得选了  只能重新加入
Looks like we have no choice but to rejoin
他们的破烂新版类星体船长俱乐部了
their dumb old new Captain Quasar club
类星体船长
今日签名
居然还找了新类星体船长来签名
They got the new Captain Quasar to sign autographs?
不得了
Impressive
不得不承认  确实不得了
I hate to admit it, but it is impressive
而且还让我想到办法了
and it gives me an idea
我是你的头号粉丝
I'm your biggest fan
不对  我才是你的头号粉丝
No, I'm your biggest fan
你能做我爹吗
Will you be my daddy?
爹
听好  艾迪
Listen, Eddie
早跟你说过别再办签名会了
I told you, no more autograph shows
我可是演员  不是书法家
I'm an actor, not a calligrapher
看看是谁爬回来了
Well, look who's come crawling back
准备好承认
Ready to admit that
类星体船长下一代
Captain Quasar: The Next Iteration
是最棒的一代了没
is the best iteration?
休想
Never
那凭什么要来我们盛大的明星签名会
Then why did you come to our big celebrity signing?
我们要把你介绍给几位老朋友
We wanted to introduce you to some old friends
你们把我们带到了什么奇异新世界来
What strange new world have you brought us to?
旧版派大机跟类星体船长吗
The old-school Pat-Tron and Captain Quasar?
你们到底上哪找来的
Where on Earth did you find them?
没到地底  是到外太空
Not on Earth, in outer space
他们飞船的坐标代码
I still had their ship's coordinates
还在派大星的旧时旅柜上面
programmed into Patrick's old time closet
我的什么了
My what now?
你的时旅柜
Your time closet
可以让你抵达一切时空
It gives you access to all of time and space?
完全没印象
Doesn't ring a bell
是装你房间里那个  就在爸妈家
It was in your room, at Mom and Dad's house?
想起来没
Remember?
啊对
Oh yeah
想起来了
I remember
谁是爸妈
Who are "Mom" and "Dad"?
总之
Anyhow
既然俩类星体跟俩派大机都到齐了
now that we've got both Quasars and both Pat-Trons here
就让他们合作拍部新剧吧
let's team 'em up for a new series
想想他们会展开怎样的精彩冒险
Just think of the exciting adventures they could have
他们可以一起烤蛋糕
They could bake a cake together
或者拼拼图
Or solve a jigsaw puzzle
或者坐在火边静静地看书
Or read quietly by the fire
听着可真精彩啊
That does sound exciting
不然还是确认哪个类星体最强好了
Or instead, let's find out who the best Quasar is
直接速战速决
once and for all
就让他们在末日无底洞里面决斗
by having them fight it out in the Pit of Doom
这地方为什么会有末日无底洞
Why does this place have a pit of doom?
那还用问
Duh
每家漫画店都有个末日无底洞
Every comic book store has a pit of doom
合情合理
That makes sense
类星体船长
Hey, Captain Quasar
他们跟我们长得好像
Those guys look exactly like us
难道他们是克隆体吗
Are they clones?
别傻了  派大机
Don't be silly, Pat-Tron
只是跟我们长得有几分像而已
They only kind of look like us
所以他们就是
That makes them
邪恶克隆体
evil clones
跟克隆我一次算你狠那集一个样
Just like in "Clone Me Once, Shame on You"
我爱看那集
I love that episode
派大机  进攻
Pat-Tron, attack
别打脸
Not the face
看来我的类星体要赢了
Well, looks like my Quasar is winning
我要抢先一步幸灾乐祸了
I'll begin gloating now to get a head start
这些克隆体太强了  船长
These clones are too strong, Captain
你说得确实  派大机
You may be right, Pat-Tron
该使出激光了
Time to use our lasers
等等  什么
Wait, what?
你们真有激光吗
You guys have real lasers?
胜利了  派大机
Victory, Pat-Tron
我们的邪恶克隆体脸都丢尽了
Our evil clones are humiliated
我们走吧
Let's get out of here
好好好
Okay
算你赢
You win
我特此宣布本类星体船长俱乐部
I hereby declare this Captain Quasar club
向各代粉丝开放
open to fans of all iterations
我的天啊  船长
Holy mackerel, Captain
是邪恶克隆体大军
An army of evil clones
它们一定是在增殖
They must be multiplying
快行动  免得它们又分裂了
Hurry, before they can split again
就好像克隆我两次算我笨那集
Just like in the episode "Clone Me Twice, Shame on Me"
史上最棒粉丝俱乐部
Best fan club ever